Benjamin Cato

With over a decade of experience in **front-end development**, I thrive on infusing projects with creativity and passion. I excel in collaborative environments and approach each project as a work of art, taking pride in my role as the artist.

402 Bridgepoint Ln.
Woodstock, GA 30189
(404) 374-1696
bcato3000@gmail.com
bcato3000.github.io/portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Whereoware, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

May 2023 - October 2023

Expertise in creating modular components via React and Storybook, employing MVC architecture, and optimizing user interfaces for Optimizely (CMS).

Perficient, Alpharetta — *Lead front-end developer*

December 2021 - May 2023

Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore/Optimizely), modular components, and applications via React and Storybook.

Fleetcor, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

August 2020 - December 2021

Collaborated with UI/UX designers and bridged the gap between graphical representations and technical implementation via vanilla JS.

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

April 2013 - July 2020

HTML5, CSS3, Sass, LESS and Javascript. Development for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore/EPI), modular/reusable components.

EDUCATION

The Creative Circus, Atlanta — *Interactive Development*

Graduate: 2012 - 2013

Chattahoochee Tech, Acworth — Computer Science

Graduate 2001 - 2003

Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw — Computer Science

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

Sass

JavaScript

TypeScript

Storybook

RESTful APIs

SPAs (React/Vue)

Node

Web components

Responsive design/dev

Cross-browser

Accessibility standards

Git

UX

Adobe creative suite

Figma

Agile/Scrum

Client-facing contributor

PC Windows

Mac iOS

1997 - 2000